<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tushar Chandra</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Tushar Chandra</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Geospatial Analytics At Scale: Analyzing Human Movement Patterns During A Pandemic</title>
      <link>/spark/2020/geospatial_analytics_esri.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 17:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/spark/2020/geospatial_analytics_esri.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How does Esri use Spark and GIS to analyze human movement? How do they use this insight to assess risk? This talk attempts to answer these.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Patterns And Anti-Patterns For Memorializing Data Science Project Artifacts</title>
      <link>/spark/2020/patterns_for_artifacts.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/spark/2020/patterns_for_artifacts.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So you need to save your work for future data scientists; how do you do this? This talk discusses best practices for saving artifacts from data science projects.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automated And Explainable Deep Learning For Clinical Language Understanding At Roche</title>
      <link>/spark/2020/clinical_decision_support_roche.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 16:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/spark/2020/clinical_decision_support_roche.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How does Roche use machine learning to help understand pathology reports? This talk gives a high-level overview of their data pipeline and tech stack, including infrastructure they&amp;rsquo;ve built up to do OCR and NLP.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Approach To Data Quality For Netflix Personalization Systems</title>
      <link>/spark/2020/data_quality_netflix.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/spark/2020/data_quality_netflix.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Netflix ingests terabytes of data and billions of rows daily, and these are used for personalized recommendations both online and offline. How do they manage data quality? By lots and lots of quality checks early on.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thursday afternoon keynotes: on deep learning and deep fakes</title>
      <link>/spark/2020/thursday_afternoon_keynotes.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/spark/2020/thursday_afternoon_keynotes.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The afternoon keynotes featured Kim Hazelwood, the west cost head of engineering at FAIR, discussing recommender systems; and Hany Farid, from UC Berkeley, discussing deepfakes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Bayesian Generative Models With Apache Spark To Solve Entity Resolution Problems At Scale</title>
      <link>/spark/2020/bayesian_generative_models.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/spark/2020/bayesian_generative_models.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Deduplication is a huge problem in many domains; this talk by two people from MavenCode discusses how they&amp;rsquo;ve used Spark-driven Bayesian generative models to solve large entity resolution problems.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Everyday Probabilistic Data Structures for Humans</title>
      <link>/spark/2020/probabilistic_data_structures.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/spark/2020/probabilistic_data_structures.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When your data gets extremely large, real-time queries can become expensive and slow. Yeshwanth Vijayakumar from Adobe discusses how &lt;em&gt;probabilistic data structures&lt;/em&gt; can help to solve these scaling problems efficiently.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes from the Thursday morning Spark keynotes</title>
      <link>/spark/2020/thursday_morning_keynotes.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/spark/2020/thursday_morning_keynotes.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The morning keynotes were more Databricks-focused; topics included updates to the Databricks workspace environment, new and upcoming features in MLflow (and that it&amp;rsquo;s joining the Linux Foundation!), and demos on &amp;ldquo;responsible AI&amp;rdquo; from Microsoft.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wednesday afternoon keynotes: racism, COVID, and politics</title>
      <link>/spark/2020/wednesday_afternoon_keynotes.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/spark/2020/wednesday_afternoon_keynotes.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The afternoon keynotes were on racism in policing, data in COVID-19, and lessons from FiveThirtyEight. Dr. Phillip Goff delivered an incredible talk on what we need to invest in to support Black communities, and Nate Silver went on with what it means to think probabilistically and work together in crisis. Amazing!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How (not) to scale deep learning in 6 easy steps</title>
      <link>/spark/2020/how_not_to_scale_deep_learning.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/spark/2020/how_not_to_scale_deep_learning.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The last talk of the morning session talked about common problems scaling ML and DL models: common pitfalls, things that people try too early (more hardware), and what to do instead.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Productionalizing Models through CI/CD Design with MLflow</title>
      <link>/spark/2020/productionalizing_models_mlflow.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 13:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/spark/2020/productionalizing_models_mlflow.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This talk, by Mary Grace Moesta &amp;amp; Peter Tamisin at Databricks, dove into MLOps and productionalization of machine learning models using MLflow. How can we apply principles from CI/CD to machine learning? And how can MLflow help us to do so?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Portable Scalable Data Visualization Techniques for Apache Spark and Python Notebook-based Analytics</title>
      <link>/spark/2020/portable_scalable_data_viz.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/spark/2020/portable_scalable_data_viz.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This talk, by Douglas Moore at Databricks, briefly discussed strategies for data visualization using Spark and different visualization libraries.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes from the Wednesday morning Spark keynotes</title>
      <link>/spark/2020/wednesday_morning_keynotes.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/spark/2020/wednesday_morning_keynotes.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Spark + AI Summit kicked off with keynotes by Ali Ghodsi (Databricks CEO), Matei Zaharia (creator of Spark) and Brooke Wenig (Databricks machine learning lead), Reynold Xin (Spark contributor), and Vishwanath Subramanian (Starbucks director of data). I wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to listen to all of it, but this post has a few highlights.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Paper] Measuring User Influence on Twitter: The Million Follower Fallacy</title>
      <link>/papers/measuring_user_influence_twitter_cha.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/papers/measuring_user_influence_twitter_cha.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This 2010 paper recently won the &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/icwsm/status/1272747094554574848&#34;&gt;ICWSM Test of Time award&lt;/a&gt;, so I gave it a look. One of the earliest papers studying Twitter, key findings include that followers are &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; a measure of engagement (but retweets and mentions are), and that influential users are influential about diverse and unrelated topics.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mindful phone usage</title>
      <link>/posts/mindfulness_and_tech.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/mindfulness_and_tech.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to use technology more mindfully, and in particular be more mindful about how I use my phone. I&amp;rsquo;m now trying to have an intention when I pick up my phone, instead of unlocking it and instinctively opening Chrome to hop on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network Propaganda, part 3</title>
      <link>/books/network_propaganda_3.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/books/network_propaganda_3.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Part 3 of the book &lt;em&gt;Network Propaganda&lt;/em&gt; is titled &amp;ldquo;The Usual Suspects,&amp;rdquo; and its focus is on the propaganda culprits who received sustained public attention. Chapter 7 focuses on the alt-right; chapter 8 Russian information operations; and chapter 9 Facebook and Cambridge Analytica.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spark Summit 2020: an early look at the schedule</title>
      <link>/posts/spark_2020_schedule.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/spark_2020_schedule.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://databricks.com/sparkaisummit/north-america-2020&#34;&gt;Spark + AI Summit&lt;/a&gt; is happening virtually next week, and I will be spending the second half of next week watching talks from there. I went through the &lt;a href=&#34;https://databricks.com/sparkaisummit/north-america-2020/agenda&#34;&gt;schedule&lt;/a&gt; to make a preliminary list of the talks that sound interesting to me. And just like &lt;a href=&#34;/spark/spark_overview.html&#34;&gt;last year&lt;/a&gt;, I&amp;rsquo;ll be writing about them here.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Paper] Fragile Masculinity: Men, Gender, and Online Harassment</title>
      <link>/papers/fragile_masculinity_online_harassment_rubin.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/papers/fragile_masculinity_online_harassment_rubin.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What motivates gendered harassment online? This paper surveys young, white, heterosexual men to reveal how anxieties about masculinity can explain endorsement of harassment towards women. Put otherwise, the online world copies the imbalances and power dynamics of the offline one.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Paper] How Well Do People Report Time Spent on Facebook?: An Evaluation of Established Survey Questions with Recommendations</title>
      <link>/papers/facebook_self_reported_survey_ernala.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/papers/facebook_self_reported_survey_ernala.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How reliable are self-reported measures of social media use? Lots of studies rely on them, but it&amp;rsquo;s well-known that self-reported behaviors can be noisy. This paper studies how noisy by comparing the results from 10 self-reported questions with actual usage data from Facebook server logs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I read this week (June 7 - 13)</title>
      <link>/what_i_read/20200613.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/what_i_read/20200613.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Back to mostly-weekly reading, this week with &amp;ldquo;Where did software go wrong?&amp;rdquo; and a piece on encouraging written communication.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
