<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>what I read on Tushar Chandra</title>
    <link>/categories/what-i-read.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in what I read on Tushar Chandra</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="/categories/what-i-read/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Resume</title>
      <link>/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resume/</guid>
      <description>&lt;style type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;.rich-text li {line-height: 1.5;}&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m currently a senior data scientist at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nielsen.com/us/en/solutions/nielsen-global-media/&#34;&gt;Nielsen&lt;/a&gt;. I did my master&amp;rsquo;s in computer science and undergrad in computer science and the &lt;a href=&#34;httpqs://www.isp.northwestern.edu/&#34;&gt;Integrated Science Program&lt;/a&gt;, both at Northwestern (go &amp;lsquo;cats!). My email address is me@(this domain).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Half a year of reading club</title>
      <link>/posts/reading_club_in_review_2020.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/reading_club_in_review_2020.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In August, I started a reading club with my friend &lt;a href=&#34;https://judahgnewman.com&#34;&gt;Judah&lt;/a&gt;. 17 papers later, this post reflects on some of the things I&amp;rsquo;ve learned.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Paper] Development of a Machine Learning Model Using Multiple, Heterogeneous Data Sources to Estimate Weekly US Suicide Fatalities</title>
      <link>/papers/weekly_suicide_prediction_choudhury.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/papers/weekly_suicide_prediction_choudhury.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How can we estimate suicides in real time when official data sources can have data lags of over a year? This paper, by researchers from Georgia Tech, the CDC, and the National Suicide Prevention Hotline, uses machine learning to model and forecast weekly suicide fatalities in the United States.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Paper] Generalists and Specialists: Using Community Embeddings to Quantify Activity Diversity in Online Platforms</title>
      <link>/papers/generalists_specialists_anderson.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/papers/generalists_specialists_anderson.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Users on online platforms might contribute to a few communities often or many communities infrequently. Can we quantify this dynamic, or quantify how similar communities are? This paper, from WWW 2019, attempts to do this through community embeddings.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Paper] Psychosocial Effects of the COVID-19 Pandemic: Large-scale Quasi-Experimental Study on Social Media</title>
      <link>/papers/psychosocial_effects_covid_saha.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/papers/psychosocial_effects_covid_saha.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How did the early months of the COVID-19 pandemic affect expressions of mental health on Twitter? This paper investigates. Through comparisons between 2020 and 2019, and clinically validated machine learning classifiers, the authors study changes in language on social media.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Paper] Biased Programmers? Or Biased Data? A Field Experiment in Operationalizing AI Ethics</title>
      <link>/papers/experiment_operationalizing_ai_ethics.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/papers/experiment_operationalizing_ai_ethics.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This study, from the NeurIPS &lt;a href=&#34;https://nbiair.com/&#34;&gt;Navigating the Broader Impacts of AI Research workshop&lt;/a&gt;, is a field experiment in algorithmic bias. Take 400 programmers and ask them to predict math performance; in what ways are their algorithms biased?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My review of The Little Book of Hygge</title>
      <link>/books/little_book_hygge.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/books/little_book_hygge.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What makes the Danes the happiest people in the world? Meik Weiking, the CEO of the Happiness Research Institute, writes a delightfully small book about the concept of &lt;em&gt;hygge&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I read this week (December 6 - December 12)</title>
      <link>/what_i_read/20201212.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/what_i_read/20201212.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Building a feature store at DoorDash, radial data visualizations, and writing programming comics.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My review of Why We Sleep</title>
      <link>/books/why_we_sleep.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/books/why_we_sleep.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Another book that I&amp;rsquo;ve read over the past couple of weeks was Matthew Walker&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Why We Sleep.&lt;/em&gt; Walker distilled perhaps the most complex biological phenomenon into an accessible 300 pages, and he taught me a lot about this essential process. (Update: maybe not!)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My review of Jenny Odell&#39;s How to Do Nothing</title>
      <link>/books/how_to_do_nothing.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/books/how_to_do_nothing.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;How to Do Nothing&lt;/em&gt; is perhaps the best book I read this year. Written as a series of loosely linked essays about finding your place in the world, Jenny Odell&amp;rsquo;s writing conveyed how deeply personal this journey is.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I read this week (November 29 - December 5)</title>
      <link>/what_i_read/20201205.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/what_i_read/20201205.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This week&amp;rsquo;s reading features the cycle of content moderation controversies (from a wonderful article titled &amp;ldquo;What Pornhub and Peloton have in common with Facebook&amp;rdquo;), along with thoughts on language servers and static site generators.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I read this week (November 22 - 28)</title>
      <link>/what_i_read/20201128.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/what_i_read/20201128.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On quirks in Ruby, leaving code better than you found it, VS Code shortcuts, and graph neural networks. Happy Thanksgiving, for those in the US!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID and Illinois</title>
      <link>/posts/covid_illinois.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/covid_illinois.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The COVID-19 situation in Illinois is dire. The media doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to be talking about it, even though the situation is presently worse here than it was in many places over the summer. What gives?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My review of Nir Eyal&#39;s Hooked</title>
      <link>/books/hooked.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/books/hooked.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I review Nir Eyal&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Hooked&lt;/em&gt;, a 200-page manual for creating habit-forming products. It&amp;rsquo;s clear that his steps work&amp;mdash;examples from several common products readily support them. But I question whether this is being used for good or evil.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I read this week (November 15 - 21)</title>
      <link>/what_i_read/20201121.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/what_i_read/20201121.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On work-life balance; writing simply; ethical issues with recommender systems; and trust and safety in products.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Paper] Decolonial AI: Decolonial Theory as Sociotechnical Foresight in Artificial Intelligence</title>
      <link>/papers/decolonial_ai_mohamed.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/papers/decolonial_ai_mohamed.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s no surprise that AI can be harmful, but discussions of AI harm often miss historical context. This paper explores the role of decolonial theories in AI to address this gap.  Through ethical foresight, the authors argue, we can rethink the role of AI in helping and harming people of different societies.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Paper] The Complementary Nature of Perceived and Actual Time Spent Online in Measuring Digital Well-being</title>
      <link>/papers/complementary_nature_time_online_mok.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/papers/complementary_nature_time_online_mok.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Self-reported measures of time spent online are known to be inaccurate compared to objective, server-log-informed measures. And while they&amp;rsquo;re each individually useful in predicting problematic effects online, little is known about how these two measures can be used alongside each other. This CSCW paper uses the open-source, open-data platform Lichess to study this.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I read this week (November 8 - 14)</title>
      <link>/what_i_read/20201114.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/what_i_read/20201114.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On rules engines and machine learning, graph theory for COVID vaccinations, MLflow and PyTorch, and grad school.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Paper] Data and Power: Archival Appraisal Theory as a Framework for Data Preservation</title>
      <link>/papers/data_and_power_archival_schoenebeck.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/papers/data_and_power_archival_schoenebeck.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Another CSCW paper for this week&amp;rsquo;s reading group; this one on digital archives. What does data preservation mean in a digital world? How do adults see their legacy? This paper draws on archival theory to study these questions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Paper] &#39;At the End of the Day Facebook Does What It Wants&#39;: How Users Experience Contesting Algorithmic Content Moderation</title>
      <link>/papers/automated_content_moderation_karahalios.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/papers/automated_content_moderation_karahalios.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When algorithms make decisions, humans should be able to appeal them. Right? This CSCW paper studies users&amp;rsquo; experience with contesting algorithmic content moderation decisions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
