<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>cscw2020 on Tushar Chandra</title>
    <link>/tags/cscw2020.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in cscw2020 on Tushar Chandra</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="/tags/cscw2020/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>[Paper] Hidden Figures: Roles and Pathways of Successful OSS Contributors</title>
      <link>/papers/hidden_figures_oss_trinkenreich.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/papers/hidden_figures_oss_trinkenreich.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This CSCW paper studies open source software contributors—all of them, not just maintainers and developers. While open source has often been looked at as a purely technical community, this paper draws attention to the other forms of work that contributors do.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I read this week (October 18 - 24)</title>
      <link>/what_i_read/20201024.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/what_i_read/20201024.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This week: on CSRankings.org, &amp;ldquo;local-first software,&amp;rdquo; and some discussion of system design interviews. Otherwise, see all the CSCW papers I&amp;rsquo;m working through!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Paper] Mitigating Exploitation: Indie Game Developers&#39; Reconfigurations of Labor in Technology</title>
      <link>/papers/mitigating_exploitations_indie_dev_freeman.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/papers/mitigating_exploitations_indie_dev_freeman.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a totally different direction from the last two CSCW papers, this work studies the indie game development industry. How does the indie community reconfigure labor in their own image? This paper explores these questions in the context of labor and technology.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Paper] Conformity of Eating Disorders through Content Moderation</title>
      <link>/papers/conformity_eating_disorders_piper.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/papers/conformity_eating_disorders_piper.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Content moderation is an essential part of online communities, but the experiences of people who are moderated are less studied. This work conducts a digital ethnography on people with eating disorders. The authors argue that moderation enforces conformity on a platform, which can further marginalize people with eating disorders.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Paper] Moving Across Lands: Online Platform Migration in Fandom Communities</title>
      <link>/papers/fandom_migrations_fiesler.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/papers/fandom_migrations_fiesler.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How do fandom communities move from platform to platform over time? What causes people to leave a platform in favor of a new one? This paper dives into community migrations in the fandom community.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My CSCW 2020 reading list</title>
      <link>/posts/cscw_reading_list.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/cscw_reading_list.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://cscw.acm.org/2020/&#34;&gt;CSCW 2020&lt;/a&gt; (on &amp;ldquo;computer-supported cooperative work and social computing&amp;rdquo;) is running from October 17th to 21st. While I&amp;rsquo;m not attending, I went through the program to look for papers that caught my eye. This post has the highlights.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Papers that I never got around to</title>
      <link>/posts/reading_list_archive_1.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/reading_list_archive_1.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In an effort to clean up my reading list, this page catalogues papers that caught my eye but that I never got around to reading.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Paper] A balanced survey on election prediction using Twitter data</title>
      <link>/papers/election_predicting_twitter_gayoavello.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/papers/election_predicting_twitter_gayoavello.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Affectionately titled &amp;ldquo;I wanted to predict elections with Twitter and all I got was this lousy paper.&amp;rdquo;
This survey paper chronicles various attempts to predict elections from Twitter, and finds that (surprise!) its predictive power has been greatly exaggerated.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I read this week (October 11 - 17)</title>
      <link>/what_i_read/20201017.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/what_i_read/20201017.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On edge cases; machine learning education; the mainstream media and real and fake news; and other, shorter work.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Paper] Evaluating the fake news problem at the scale of the information ecosystem</title>
      <link>/papers/fake_news_information_ecosystem_watts.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/papers/fake_news_information_ecosystem_watts.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What is the role of fake news in the overall media ecosystem?
Conventional wisdom might say it&amp;rsquo;s significant, but this paper provides evidence for the opposite.
Using datasets of cross-platform media viewing, the authors find that fake news represents a small proportion of overall media consumption.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Paper] Deconstructing the Filter Bubble: User Decision-Making and Recommender Systems</title>
      <link>/papers/deconstructing_filter_bubble_aridor.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/papers/deconstructing_filter_bubble_aridor.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the more surprising research findings is that filter bubbles arise even in the absence of recommendation.
How does this happen, and what can be done to alleviate it?
This RecSys 2020 paper investigates by modeling recommender systems with numerical simulation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Materials for my PyMCon talk</title>
      <link>/posts/pymcon_talk.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/pymcon_talk.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This post contains materials for my PyMCon talk, &lt;em&gt;Learning Bayesian Statistics with Pokemon GO&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I read this week (October 4 - 10)</title>
      <link>/what_i_read/20201010.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/what_i_read/20201010.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This week&amp;rsquo;s reading: why finishing a personal project is hard, a GPT-3 bot posing as a human, more findings from Cambridge Analytica, and an interview with Safiya Noble.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resources to learn about Bayesian inference</title>
      <link>/posts/bayesian_resources.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/bayesian_resources.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a companion post to my upcoming PyMCon talk, &lt;em&gt;Learning Bayesian Statistics with Pokemon GO&lt;/em&gt;. I want to catalog resources that helped me to learn Bayesian inference for the benefit of others trying to do the same.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My favorite Python 3.9 feature isn&#39;t a 3.9 feature</title>
      <link>/posts/python_39_generics.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/python_39_generics.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Python 3.9 was released this week, and with it come a few incremental features. But my favorite feature isn&amp;rsquo;t just in Python 3.9&amp;mdash;it&amp;rsquo;s usable in 3.7 and up.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Paper] &#39;Data Strikes&#39;: Evaluating the Effectiveness of a New Form of Collective Action Against Technology Companies</title>
      <link>/papers/data_strikes_vincent.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/papers/data_strikes_vincent.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What do you do when &amp;ldquo;hit a company where it hurts&amp;rdquo; means their data, or their models? What does it mean to go on a &amp;ldquo;data strike&amp;rdquo;? This paper studies the idea of withholding one&amp;rsquo;s personal data and evaluates its impact on  recommender systems.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I read this week (September 27 - October 3)</title>
      <link>/what_i_read/20201003.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/what_i_read/20201003.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This week: a multi-armed bandit and a opinion dynamics model, both written in Julia by chance. That sparked a rabbit hole of reading about the language.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Paper] Improving fairness in machine learning systems: What do industry practitioners need?</title>
      <link>/papers/improving_fairness_practitioner_needs_holstein.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/papers/improving_fairness_practitioner_needs_holstein.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s lots of research on what (un)fairness in machine learning looks like. But what do industry practitioners actually need to address fairness issues? This paper surveys them to find out.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I read this week (September 20 - September 26)</title>
      <link>/what_i_read/20200926.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/what_i_read/20200926.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This week&amp;rsquo;s reading, including &amp;ldquo;Useful things to know about engineering levels,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Enable learning in technical writing,&amp;rdquo; and more.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Paper] Reliance on Metrics is a Fundamental Challenge for AI</title>
      <link>/papers/reliance_metrics_problem_thomas.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/papers/reliance_metrics_problem_thomas.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of my more deeply held beliefs is that people rely too heavily on metrics, so when my friend Judah sent me this paper I was quick to jump on it. Rachel Thomas and David Uminsky argue that an overemphasis on metrics is a fundamental problem with AI.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
