<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>www on Tushar Chandra</title>
    <link>/tags/www.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in www on Tushar Chandra</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="/tags/www/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>[Paper] A Comparison of Approaches to Advertising Measurement: Evidence from Big Field Experiments at Facebook</title>
      <link>/papers/facebook_advertising_field_study_gordon.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/papers/facebook_advertising_field_study_gordon.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In what is probably my last digital advertising paper for now, I read a paper out of Kellogg + Facebook studying the causal effects of digital advertising. This is the nail in the coffin of my belief that digital advertising is overhyped and overvalued, and that they do far less than anyone appears to believe.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A disaster in Iowa</title>
      <link>/posts/iowa_caucus_disaster.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/iowa_caucus_disaster.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Like many on Monday, I left work eagerly awaiting the results of the Iowa caucuses happening one state west of me. I got home, cooked dinner, and opened up the &lt;a href=&#34;https://fivethirtyeight.com/live-blog/iowa-caucus-2020-election-live/&#34;&gt;FiveThirtyEight live blog&lt;/a&gt; to start following election results. A couple of hours passed, and it became increasingly clear that something had gone very, very wrong.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three article summaries (on grad school advice)</title>
      <link>/what_i_read/20200205.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/what_i_read/20200205.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Three article summaries, which I&amp;rsquo;m breaking out from my usual &amp;ldquo;what I read&amp;rdquo; posts because of the common theme (of CS research &amp;amp; grad school) that connects them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I read this week (January 26 - February 1)</title>
      <link>/what_i_read/20200201.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/what_i_read/20200201.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Articles I read this week, including about Python 3.9, regulation of tech companies, and a host of short articles.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talk Notes: The Global Energy Challenge by Michael Greenstone</title>
      <link>/posts/talk_global_energy_challenge.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/talk_global_energy_challenge.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I had the pleasure of hearing &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.michaelgreenstone.com/&#34;&gt;Michael Greenstone&lt;/a&gt;, former Chief Economist to President Obama and now professor at UChicago, speak about the Global Energy Challenge. These are my notes and my thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Paper] Norms Matter: Contrasting Social Support Around Behavior Change in Online Weight Loss Communities</title>
      <link>/papers/contrasting_social_support_chancellor.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/papers/contrasting_social_support_chancellor.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My last of Dr. Chancellor&amp;rsquo;s papers for now. This paper studies the discourse within two online health communities for weight loss, /r/loseit and (the now banned) /r/proED. The authors discuss how different communities provide support differently and discuss design implications.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Paper] Multimodal Classification of Moderated Online Pro-Eating Disorder Content</title>
      <link>/papers/classification_pro_ed_chancellor.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/papers/classification_pro_ed_chancellor.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is another social computing paper that develops a deep learning classifier for pro-eating disorder content on Tumblr. This work bridges the gap between deep learning and social computing, contributing an image+text classifier for identifying deviant posts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I read this week (January 19 - 25)</title>
      <link>/what_i_read/20200125.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/what_i_read/20200125.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Articles I read this week, including &amp;ldquo;data science is different now&amp;rdquo; and a Washington Post editorial about regulating AI.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparing my old and new sites, part 2</title>
      <link>/posts/site_comparison_part2.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/site_comparison_part2.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a &lt;a href=&#34;/posts/site_comparison.html&#34;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt;, I compared the features of my old and new site. This is part 2 of that post, focusing on things that I missed then that have only come up after a few weeks of using the site.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I read this week (January 12 - 18)</title>
      <link>/what_i_read/20200118.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/what_i_read/20200118.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Articles I read this week, including &amp;ldquo;goodbye clean code,&amp;rdquo; the Neural ODEs paper retrospective, and technical writing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software engineering is an essential part of data science</title>
      <link>/posts/software_in_dsci.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/software_in_dsci.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Good software engineering is an indispensible part of good data science. I&amp;rsquo;ve believed this for a while, but only recently come to feel strongly about it, and this post goes into more detail on why.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Paper] &#39;This Post Will Just Get Taken Down&#39;: Characterizing Removed Pro-Eating Disorder Content on Social Media</title>
      <link>/papers/removed_pro_ed_chancellor.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/papers/removed_pro_ed_chancellor.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a social computing paper analyzing characteristics of over 30,000 pro-eating disorder (pro-ED) posts that were removed from Instagram after having been public at one time. The authors built a classifier for removed pro-ED posts against non-removed ones, and also studied the characteristics of removed posts more generally. Published in CHI 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I read this week (January 5 - 11)</title>
      <link>/what_i_read/20200111.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/what_i_read/20200111.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Articles I read this week, including predictions for 2020 and FiveThirtyEight&amp;rsquo;s primary methodology.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparing my old and new sites</title>
      <link>/posts/site_comparison.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/site_comparison.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I migrated my site a couple of days ago. What are some of the differences, both feature-wise and visually? I&amp;rsquo;ll compare common actions on both.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I read this week (December 29 - January 4)</title>
      <link>/what_i_read/20200104.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/what_i_read/20200104.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Articles I read this week, including the future of the web and different ways of conveying information, thoughts on the current state of software, and more.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Paper] Competition and Crowd-out for Brand Keywords in Sponsored Search</title>
      <link>/papers/competition_crowd_out_simonov.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2020 15:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/papers/competition_crowd_out_simonov.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Another paper on digital search advertising, this one on the effects of competition on ads placed on brand keyword searches. This was another study reacting to the eBay study on own-brand advertising.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Paper] Firms&#39; Reactions to Public Information on Business Practices: Case of Search Advertising</title>
      <link>/papers/reactions_to_search_ads_rao.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2020 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/papers/reactions_to_search_ads_rao.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a paper evaluating the effects of the infamous eBay online advertising experiment, in which eBay pulled millions of dollars of own-brand advertising and saw no measurable effect on web traffic. The study (using data from Bing) evaluated how other companies reacted to this news.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrating to Hugo</title>
      <link>/posts/migrating_to_hugo.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/migrating_to_hugo.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello, Hugo! This post marks the first one written specifically for the new version of my site, built with &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll outline some of the reasons for switching to Hugo and talk about the process of moving everything over.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading List</title>
      <link>/reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/reading/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a page of things I&amp;rsquo;m hoping to read &amp;ldquo;soon&amp;rdquo; (for some value of soon). It&amp;rsquo;s some cross between a digital bookshelf and public bookmarks, where I drop papers that cross my radar or blog posts, talks, or other ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of these I&amp;rsquo;ve printed out and carry around with me. Others are unlikely to ever be read because they&amp;rsquo;re so far out of my areas of expertise or interest. While this page is mostly for my own reference, it also pretty broadly shows the types of work I&amp;rsquo;m interested in.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Paper] Discrimination in the Age of Algorithms (2/2)</title>
      <link>/papers/discrimination_algorithms_kleinberg_2.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/papers/discrimination_algorithms_kleinberg_2.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How do we regulate algorithms? How can they help us to create equity? This is part 2 of my summary of the paper by Kleinberg et al.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
