<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tags on Tushar Chandra</title>
    <link>/tags.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tags on Tushar Chandra</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="/tags/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>What I read this week (July 19 - 25)</title>
      <link>/what_i_read/20200725.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/what_i_read/20200725.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m spending a lot of time reading Cathy O&amp;rsquo;Neil&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Weapons of Math Destruction&lt;/em&gt;, which is excellent. This week&amp;rsquo;s articles include advice for grad students and some advice on software engineering.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Papers] Two more papers from the ICML Participatory Approaches to ML workshop</title>
      <link>/papers/icml_workshop_papers_2.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/papers/icml_workshop_papers_2.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Two more papers in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://participatoryml.github.io/&#34;&gt;Participatory Approaches to Machine Learning&lt;/a&gt; workshop at ICML 2020. These are more directly about participation: &lt;em&gt;Participation is not a Design Fix for Machine Learning&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;What If I Don&amp;rsquo;t Like Any Of The Choices? The Limits of Preference Elicitation for Participatory Algorithm Design&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Papers] Two recommender systems papers from the ICML Participatory Approaches to ML workshop</title>
      <link>/papers/icml_workshop_papers.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/papers/icml_workshop_papers.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://participatoryml.github.io/&#34;&gt;Participatory Approaches to Machine Learning&lt;/a&gt; workshop at ICML 2020 caught my attention, and so I read two papers on recommender systems that came out of it: &lt;em&gt;Deconstructing the Filter Bubble: User Decision-Making and Recommender Systems&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Designing Recommender Systems with Reachability in Mind&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Paper] What are you optimizing for? Aligning Recommender Systems with Human Values</title>
      <link>/papers/aligning_recommender_human_values_stray.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/papers/aligning_recommender_human_values_stray.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How can recommender systems better align to human values, like fairness, diversity, or equity? This paper, from the ICML Participatory Approaches to ML workshop, discusses approaches to answering this question.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I read this week (July 12 - July 18)</title>
      <link>/what_i_read/20200718.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/what_i_read/20200718.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This week, all the blog posts and articles I read came from &lt;a href=&#34;https://pointer.io&#34;&gt;Pointer&lt;/a&gt;. I spent most of my free time finishing up the book &lt;em&gt;Twenty Six Words&lt;/em&gt; (highly recommend!) and then starting &lt;em&gt;Weapons of Math Destruction&lt;/em&gt; by Cathy O&amp;rsquo;Neil.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The future of Section 230</title>
      <link>/books/twenty_six_words_4.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/books/twenty_six_words_4.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What comes next for Section 230? What comes next for the platforms who have used Section 230 as a shield for so long?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Internet Exceptionalism</title>
      <link>/books/twenty_six_words_3.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/books/twenty_six_words_3.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In my second-to-last post on Section 230, I discuss the idea of internet exceptionalism&amp;mdash;how, in passing Section 230, Congress decided that the internet should be different than other publishing mediums.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I read this week (July 5 - July 11)</title>
      <link>/what_i_read/20200711.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/what_i_read/20200711.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This week, I watched a few talks from SciPy 2020 and continued my reading on &lt;em&gt;Twenty-Six Words&lt;/em&gt;; this post mostly contains the talks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I read this week (June 28 - July 4)</title>
      <link>/what_i_read/20200704.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/what_i_read/20200704.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This week&amp;rsquo;s reading was all over the place: a talk on Docker and Python for data science, authorial intent in code, the book &lt;em&gt;Clean Code&lt;/em&gt;, and an essay on NPM.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CompuServe and Prodigy: a story about the early internet</title>
      <link>/books/twenty_six_words_2.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/books/twenty_six_words_2.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is my second post on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jeffkosseff.com/home&#34;&gt;The Twenty-Six Words That Created The Internet&lt;/a&gt;, by Jeff Kosseff. Chapter 2 tells the story of two online service providers, CompuServe and Prodigy, and how litigation against them with opposite outcomes set the scene for the passing of Section 230.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magazines and the Internet</title>
      <link>/books/twenty_six_words_1.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/books/twenty_six_words_1.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m now starting to read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jeffkosseff.com/home&#34;&gt;The Twenty-Six Words That Created The Internet&lt;/a&gt;, by Jeff Kosseff, which refers to Section 230 of the Communciations Decency Act. Section 230 is under attack by politicians on both sides, and debates about misinformation and hate speech on social media have become more heated lately, so I became interested in the legal basis for their protections. This post discusses early rulings on freedom of speech and press, prior to the creation of the internet, that helped shape 230.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spark 2020 Summary</title>
      <link>/spark/2020/summary.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/spark/2020/summary.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My summary of the talks I watched at Spark + AI Summit this year, and recommendations for what to watch after the fact.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Another website redesign</title>
      <link>/posts/another_new_layout.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/another_new_layout.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My homepage has been given a new look&amp;mdash;still Hugo, but now powered by my own custom layout and Tailwind CSS. This post is a technical dive into the process of rebuilding it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network Propaganda, part 4</title>
      <link>/books/network_propaganda_4.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/books/network_propaganda_4.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Part 4 of the book &lt;em&gt;Network Propaganda&lt;/em&gt; is titled &amp;ldquo;Can Democracy Survive the Internet?&amp;quot;, and it focuses on how polarization came to be, how the media ecosystem came to be the way that it is, and proposed interventions (most realistically, regulating political advertising).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I read this week (June 21 - 27)</title>
      <link>/what_i_read/20200627.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/what_i_read/20200627.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This week&amp;rsquo;s reading had a presentation about CS education within higher education and another blog post by Will Larson. Most of my time was taken up by Spark Summit and rebuilding (again!) this site&amp;rsquo;s layout.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Apache Spark And Differential Privacy For Protecting The Privacy Of The 2020 Census Respondents</title>
      <link>/spark/2020/census_differential_privacy.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/spark/2020/census_differential_privacy.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As the 2020 Census is happening, the US Census Bureau has developed a new system to use differential privacy to protect people&amp;rsquo;s personal data. This talk describes what motivated this system (being able to reconstruct personal data in 2010&amp;mdash;oh no!) and how they created a differential privacy algorithm to help them out.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scoring At Scale: Generating Follow Recommendations For Over 690 Million LinkedIn Members</title>
      <link>/spark/2020/follow_recommendations_linkedin.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 13:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/spark/2020/follow_recommendations_linkedin.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How does LinkedIn generate follow recommendations for hundreds of millions of users and entities? Anything involving large shuffles is a non-starter; this talk describes how they developed a custom hash-partitioned join algorithm to handle such large data.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generalized SEIR Model On Large Networks</title>
      <link>/spark/2020/generalized_seir_models.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/spark/2020/generalized_seir_models.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SEIR models for epidemiology break down a population into four partitions: susceptible, exposed, infected, and recovered. This talk gives an overview of how &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ryansmcgee/seirsplus&#34;&gt;seirsplus&lt;/a&gt; can be used with MLflow and hyperopt to run simulations and experiments of possible COVID-19 scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automated Testing For Protecting Data Pipelines from Undocumented Assumptions</title>
      <link>/spark/2020/automated_testing_undocumented_assumptions.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 12:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/spark/2020/automated_testing_undocumented_assumptions.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Data pipelines are fraught with undocumented assumptions: about column data types, nullability, acceptable values, and more. Automated unit testing often fails to catch violations of these assumptions. The speakers from Superconductive introduce &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/great-expectations/great_expectations&#34;&gt;Great Expectations&lt;/a&gt;, a library to build these assumptions into a data pipeline.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Democratizing PySpark For Mobile Game Publishing</title>
      <link>/spark/2020/democratizing_pyspark.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/spark/2020/democratizing_pyspark.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This talk, by Ben Weber of Zynga, talks about their experiences making their PySpark environment available to everyone in their analytics function. Democratizing PySpark in this way, while not easy, helped to improve their analytics function.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
